<?xml version="1.0"?>
<report>
  <agency>NASA</agency>
  <generated>2014-08-28 19:47:31</generated>
  <items>
    <item id="2.1">
      <parent/>
      <text>Engage with customers to identify at least two existing major customer-facing services that contain high-value data or content as first-move candidates to make compliant with new open data, content, and web API policy.</text>
      <due>90 Days</due>
      <due_date>2012/08/21</due_date>
      <fields>
        <field>
          <type>select</type>
          <name>2-1-status</name>
          <label>Overall Status</label>
          <options>
            <option>
              <label>Not Started</label>
              <value>not-started</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>In Progress</label>
              <value>in-progress</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>Completed</label>
              <value>completed</value>
            </option>
          </options>
          <value>completed</value>
        </field>
      </fields>
      <multiple/>
    </item>
    <item id="2.1.1">
      <parent>2.1</parent>
      <text>Paragraph on customer engagement approach</text>
      <due>90 days</due>
      <due_date>2012/08/21</due_date>
      <fields>
        <field>
          <type>textarea</type>
          <name>2-1-1-customer-engagement-approach</name>
          <label>Paragraph on customer engagement approach</label>
          <options/>
          <value>NASA has three phases defined for Customer Engagement for Open Data.   Phase One included the development of code.nasa.gov and data.nasa.gov.  Code.nasa.gov and data.nasa.gov, are two major ways that NASA engages our customers. Code.nasa.gov website expands NASA&#x2019;s open source activities, surfaces existing activities, provides a discussion forum, and guides internal and external groups in open development, release, and contribution.  NASA hopes to lower barriers to building open technology in partnership with the public. &#xD;
Phase Two concentrates on open source concepts, policies, and activities at NASA, and is ongoing across the agency.   &#xD;
Phase Three focuses on building software tools to improve and speed open source development, including distributed version control, issue tracking, continuous integration, and documentation. Data.nasa.gov is NASA&#x2019;s commitment to open data and expands the audience for the vast body of knowledge produced through NASA aeronautics and space missions.. Developers, technologists, entrepreneurs, citizen scientists and many others can contribute directly to the exploration of space and Earth by helping to create new ways to leverage NASA data. As part of the Open Government Initiative and the Open Data Policy, the Agency is working to improve accessibility to this data and incentivizing the use of government data by citizens through challenge programs, such as the International Space Apps Challenge. NASA makes available data, software, and analytic tools through the Open.NASA.gov website that links to both the data.NASA.gov and the code.NASA.gov catalogs &#x2013; which draw from NASA&#x2019;s many mission-related websites. The public now has streamlined access to publically available data and tools with information and direct links to approximately over 3000 datasets.&#xD;
Additionally, NASA requests feedback via comments on Open.NASA.gov and NASA&#x2019;s Digital Strategy website for data sets or digital information the public finds most valuable.   The public can also submit a request on Github.&#xD;
</value>
        </field>
      </fields>
      <multiple/>
    </item>
    <item id="2.1.2">
      <parent>2.1</parent>
      <text>Prioritized list of systems (datasets)</text>
      <due>90 days</due>
      <due_date>2012/08/21</due_date>
      <fields>
        <field>
          <type>text</type>
          <name>2-1-2-name</name>
          <label>System Name</label>
          <options/>
          <value>
            <value>NASA Data API</value>
            <value>ISS Live API</value>
            <value>ExoAPI</value>
          </value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>text</type>
          <name>2-1-2-description</name>
          <label>System Description</label>
          <options/>
          <value>
            <value>The data.nasa.gov API allows a machine-readable interface to return metadata from the site organized by category, tag, date, or search term. We&#x2019;re hoping this allows new and creative visualizations of the data resources NASA provides to the public. Additionally, it is a learning experience for us as we work to expand transparency, participation, and collaboration at NASA through new uses of technology.</value>
            <value>Thousands of data points are downloaded every minute from the Station, and ISS Live! makes a broad set of that data open and accessible. Furthermore,  ISS Live! will make an application programming interface (API) available as a web service for external developers to take ISS data and put it into their own websites and mobile applications.</value>
            <value>ExoAPI is an ongoing project that extends the accessibility of exoplanetary data by providing an easy to use RESTful API. ExoAPI was created during the NASA Space Apps Challenge by a team of three amazing geniuses who knew nothing about space before they started this...and still don't really. Currently the data is provided by http://exoplanetology.blogspot.com/ who in turn feeds the data from http://exoplanet.eu/. The ExoAPI team plans on extending the API to encompass a wider array of data sources and more interesting space data to reach as many programmers as possible and encourage an explosion of space data based mashups. </value>
          </value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>select</type>
          <name>2-1-2-scope</name>
          <label>System Scope</label>
          <options>
            <option>
              <label>Internal</label>
              <value>internal</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>External</label>
              <value>external</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>Both</label>
              <value>both</value>
            </option>
          </options>
          <value>
            <value>both</value>
            <value>both</value>
            <value>both</value>
          </value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>text</type>
          <name>2-1-2-customer</name>
          <label>Main Customer</label>
          <options/>
          <value>
            <value>Employees, Citizens</value>
            <value>Employees, Citizens</value>
            <value>Employees, Citizens</value>
          </value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>text</type>
          <name>2-1-2-uii</name>
          <label>Unique Investment Identifier</label>
          <options/>
          <value>
            <value>026-000000001</value>
            <value>026-000000001</value>
            <value>026-000000001</value>
          </value>
        </field>
      </fields>
      <multiple>1</multiple>
    </item>
    <item id="7.1">
      <parent/>
      <text>Engage with customers to identify at least two existing priority customer-facing services to optimize for mobile use.</text>
      <due>90 Days</due>
      <due_date>2012/08/21</due_date>
      <fields>
        <field>
          <type>select</type>
          <name>7-1-status</name>
          <label>Overall Status</label>
          <options>
            <option>
              <label>Not Started</label>
              <value>not-started</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>In Progress</label>
              <value>in-progress</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>Completed</label>
              <value>completed</value>
            </option>
          </options>
          <value>completed</value>
        </field>
      </fields>
      <multiple/>
    </item>
    <item id="7.1.1">
      <parent>7.1</parent>
      <text>Paragraph on customer engagement approach</text>
      <due>90 days</due>
      <due_date>2012/08/21</due_date>
      <fields>
        <field>
          <type>textarea</type>
          <name>7-1-1-customer-engagement-approach</name>
          <label>Paragraph on customer engagement approach</label>
          <options/>
          <value>NASA is a leader in providing open data to citizens, researchers, and fellow agencies. Our NASA vision is to &#x201C;to reach for new heights and reveal the unknown so that what we do and learn will benefit all humankind.&#x201D; We do this by sharing our discoveries as widely as possible. We've embarked on an ambitious citizen engagement through our crowdsourcing and challenge portfolio, where we allow our customers -- the taxpayer -- to engage with us to create innovative new solutions to problems facing humanity, both on and off the planet. NASA leads the public sector in the breadth and depth of experience and experimentation with prizes, citizen science, and challenges, much of which is based on NASA's openly available data and tools. From the International Space Apps Challenge, to Centennial Challenges, to NASA's Open Innovation Pavilion, and NASA Tournament Lab, citizens can join our journey of exploration.  Through these citizen engagement programs, NASA provides priority high value datasets -- created as an output of NASA&#x2019;s scientific and engineering programs &#x2013; to allow the public to create innovative solutions and new products for social good, non-profit, and commercial gain. The International Space Apps Challenge, in its third year, engaged with over 8000 citizens from 95 cities and 46 countries, to create a harvest of innovation from the seeds of NASA data. We are committed to increase our customer engagement through innovative data programs to infuse innovation at the local level, as well as spurring new ways to do business in the federal government. </value>
        </field>
      </fields>
      <multiple/>
    </item>
    <item id="7.1.2">
      <parent>7.1</parent>
      <text>Prioritized list of systems (datasets)</text>
      <due>90 days</due>
      <due_date>2012/08/21</due_date>
      <fields>
        <field>
          <type>text</type>
          <name>7-1-2-name</name>
          <label>System Name</label>
          <options/>
          <value>
            <value>NASA Apps Store</value>
            <value>WebTADS</value>
            <value>Visualization Explorer</value>
            <value>people.nasa.gov</value>
          </value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>text</type>
          <name>7-1-2-description</name>
          <label>System Description</label>
          <options/>
          <value>
            <value>Provide employees and contractors with access to agency data and systems on the go.</value>
            <value>WebTADS Mobile is a lighter version of the desktop-based WebTADS developed to provide NASA Civil Servants with the convenience of recording time when they're not in the office or connected via VPN.</value>
            <value>NASA Visualization Explorer, the coolest way to get stories about advanced space-based research delivered right to your iPad. A direct connection to NASA&#x2019;s extraordinary fleet of research spacecraft, this app presents cutting edge research stories in an engaging and exciting format. </value>
            <value>NASA Enterprise Directory (NED) Search</value>
          </value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>select</type>
          <name>7-1-2-scope</name>
          <label>System Scope</label>
          <options>
            <option>
              <label>Internal</label>
              <value>internal</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>External</label>
              <value>external</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>Both</label>
              <value>both</value>
            </option>
          </options>
          <value>
            <value>internal</value>
            <value>internal</value>
            <value>both</value>
            <value>both</value>
          </value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>text</type>
          <name>7-1-2-customer</name>
          <label>Main Customer</label>
          <options/>
          <value>
            <value>Employees</value>
            <value>Employees</value>
            <value>Employees, Citizens</value>
            <value>Employees, Citizens</value>
          </value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>text</type>
          <name>7-1-2-uii</name>
          <label>Unique Investment Identifier</label>
          <options/>
          <value>
            <value>026-000000001</value>
            <value>026-000000001</value>
            <value>026-000004110</value>
            <value>026-000000001</value>
          </value>
        </field>
      </fields>
      <multiple>1</multiple>
    </item>
    <item id="4.2">
      <parent/>
      <text>Establish an agency-wide governance structure for developing and delivering digital services</text>
      <due>6 months</due>
      <due_date>2012/11/23</due_date>
      <fields>
        <field>
          <type>select</type>
          <name>4-2-status</name>
          <label>Overall Status</label>
          <options>
            <option>
              <label>Not Started</label>
              <value>not-started</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>In Progress</label>
              <value>in-progress</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>Completed</label>
              <value>completed</value>
            </option>
          </options>
          <value>completed</value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>textarea</type>
          <name>4-2-policy</name>
          <label>Paragraph on Governance</label>
          <options/>
          <value>In responding to Milestone 4.2 of the Digital Government Strategy, NASA followed the Advisory Group&#x2019;s encouragement to &#x201C;build upon existing structures and processes as much as possible.&#x201D;  To cover the gaps in existing governance structures, NASA is creating a Digital Services Council to be co-chaired by the Chief Information Officer and Associate Administrator for Communications. The official memo, signed March 3, 2014 outlined the creation of a Digital Services Council with representation from Mission Directorates, Centers, and Headquarters to provide leadership and direction for digital services &#x2013; including data, information, platforms, and tools. NASA is currently working through the logistics for setting up the Council: drafting the charter, recruiting membership, and determining topics that bridge digital service requirements between the Office of Communications and CIO.</value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>text</type>
          <name>4-2-link</name>
          <label>URL to Governance Document</label>
          <options/>
          <value>http://www.nasa.gov/agency/digitalstrategy/governance.html</value>
        </field>
      </fields>
      <multiple/>
    </item>
    <item id="5.2">
      <parent/>
      <text>Develop an enterprise-wide inventory of mobile devices and wireless service contracts</text>
      <due>6 months</due>
      <due_date>2012/11/23</due_date>
      <fields>
        <field>
          <type>select</type>
          <name>5-2-status</name>
          <label>Overall Status</label>
          <options>
            <option>
              <label>Not Started</label>
              <value>not-started</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>In Progress</label>
              <value>in-progress</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>Completed</label>
              <value>completed</value>
            </option>
          </options>
          <value>completed</value>
        </field>
      </fields>
      <multiple/>
    </item>
    <item id="5.2.1">
      <parent>5.2</parent>
      <text>Develop wireless and mobile inventory</text>
      <due>6 months</due>
      <due_date>2012/11/23</due_date>
      <fields>
        <field>
          <type>text</type>
          <name>5-2-1-component</name>
          <label>Bureau/Component</label>
          <options/>
          <value>
            <value>OCIO</value>
          </value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>select</type>
          <name>5-2-1-inventory-status</name>
          <label>Inventory Status</label>
          <options>
            <option>
              <label>Not Started</label>
              <value>not-started</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>In Progress</label>
              <value>in-progress</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>Completed</label>
              <value>completed</value>
            </option>
          </options>
          <value>
            <value>completed</value>
          </value>
        </field>
      </fields>
      <multiple>1</multiple>
    </item>
    <item id="8.2">
      <parent/>
      <text>Implement performance and customer satisfaction measuring tools on all .gov websites</text>
      <due>8 months</due>
      <due_date>2013/1/22</due_date>
      <fields>
        <field>
          <type>select</type>
          <name>8-2-status</name>
          <label>Overall Status</label>
          <options>
            <option>
              <label>Not Started</label>
              <value>not-started</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>In Progress</label>
              <value>in-progress</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>Completed</label>
              <value>completed</value>
            </option>
          </options>
          <value>completed</value>
        </field>
      </fields>
      <multiple/>
    </item>
    <item id="8.2.1">
      <parent>8.2</parent>
      <text>Implement performance measurement tool</text>
      <due>8 months</due>
      <due_date>2013/1/22</due_date>
      <fields>
        <field>
          <type>select</type>
          <name>8-2-1-tool</name>
          <label>Implemented Digital Analytics Program</label>
          <options>
            <option>
              <label>Yes</label>
              <value>yes</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>No</label>
              <value>no</value>
            </option>
          </options>
          <value>yes</value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>textarea</type>
          <name>8-2-1-implementation</name>
          <label>If Not, Describe Implementation</label>
          <options/>
          <value/>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>text</type>
          <name>8-2-1-percent</name>
          <label>Percent of websites covered</label>
          <options/>
          <value>100</value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>text</type>
          <name>8-2-1-url</name>
          <label>URL of performance data</label>
          <options/>
          <value>https://www.google.com/analytics/web/?authuser=1#my-reports/N_nOya0_SVC3_IfT9hgbkw/a33523145w60822123p68619810/</value>
        </field>
      </fields>
      <multiple/>
    </item>
    <item id="8.2.2">
      <parent>8.2</parent>
      <text>Implement customer satisfaction tool</text>
      <due>8 months</due>
      <due_date>2013/1/22</due_date>
      <fields>
        <field>
          <type>textarea</type>
          <name>8-2-2-implementation</name>
          <label>Describe Implementation</label>
          <options/>
          <value> The main www.nasa.gov website uses ForeSee Feedback analytics that enables the agency to offer the opportunity for citizens to volunteer allow the agency to follow their movements throughout the website before offering a short survey measuring their satisfaction at the conclusion of their visit.</value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>text</type>
          <name>8-2-2-url</name>
          <label>URL of performance data</label>
          <options/>
          <value>http://www.nasa.gov/pdf/598263main_NASA%20Customer%20Service%20Plan.pdf</value>
        </field>
      </fields>
      <multiple/>
    </item>
    <item id="1.2">
      <parent/>
      <text>Ensure all new IT systems follow the open data, content, and web API policy and operationalize agency.gov/developer pages</text>
      <due>12 months</due>
      <due_date>2013/05/23</due_date>
      <fields>
        <field>
          <type>select</type>
          <name>1-2-status</name>
          <label>Overall Status</label>
          <options>
            <option>
              <label>Not Started</label>
              <value>not-started</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>In Progress</label>
              <value>in-progress</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>Completed</label>
              <value>completed</value>
            </option>
          </options>
          <value>in-progress</value>
        </field>
      </fields>
      <multiple/>
    </item>
    <item id="1.2.1">
      <parent>1.2</parent>
      <text>Document policy for architecting new IT systems for openness by default</text>
      <due>6 months</due>
      <due_date>2012/11/23</due_date>
      <fields>
        <field>
          <type>textarea</type>
          <name>1-2-1-description</name>
          <label>Describe policy</label>
          <options/>
          <value>NASA is in the process of reviewing the recently released open data policy. The agency's long tradition of sharing its work and research with the public mean that much of our data already meets the requirements laid out in the policy, and the agency plans a comprehensive response to ensure that additional data is released in formats that are open, accessible, and of value to the public.&#xD;
NASA is also currently working on contract language to be put in place for all new IT systems such that hooks are provided to allow exposure of data in a machine-readable manner.  Additionally, the NASA Information Architecture Management initiative, run out of Office of Chief Information Officer, is providing data guidelines and standards that show reference architectures and implementations for best-practices approaches to machine-readable data and data operability.</value>
        </field>
      </fields>
      <multiple/>
    </item>
    <item id="1.2.4">
      <parent>1.2</parent>
      <text>Develop Data Inventory Schedule - Summary</text>
      <due>17 months</due>
      <due_date>2013/10/23</due_date>
      <fields>
        <field>
          <type>textarea</type>
          <name>1-2-4-data-inventory-schedule-summary</name>
          <label>Summarize the Inventory Schedule</label>
          <options/>
          <value>NASA was founded on the principles of transparency and openness via the 1958 Space Act with requires NASA to &#x201C;provide for the widest practicable and appropriate dissemination of information concernting the activities and the results thereof.&#x201D; NASA datasets are available on NASA.gov websites for use by the public. Due to the sheer volume of NASA&#x2019;s data, converting these datasets to machine-readable format is more of a marathon than a sprint. We are committed to making our data as accessible as possible, and are working with the agency Mission Directorates to identify, collect, and format existing data that is routinely made available through open sources, most often mission program websites. &#xD;
With an unfunded mandate to convert our datasets to machine-readable files, we are redirecting resources, as available, to convert information about the nature of the Universe, how life begins, friendly Earth-like planets, aerodynamic models, engineering designs, and more. We have much to offer and our data sets are highly sought after. Our schedule represents an good-faith attempt to provide mission-focused high value datasets through an orderly process&#xD;
Earth Science: July 2014&#xD;
Space Science: August 2014 (towards the August 31, 2014 quarterly submission date)&#xD;
Space Technology: September 2014&#xD;
Human Spaceflight: October 2014&#xD;
Aeronautics: November 2014  (towards the November 30, 2014 quarterly submission date)&#xD;
</value>
        </field>
      </fields>
      <multiple/>
    </item>
    <item id="1.2.5">
      <parent>1.2</parent>
      <text>Develop Data Inventory Schedule - Milestones</text>
      <due>17 months</due>
      <due_date>2013/10/23</due_date>
      <fields>
        <field>
          <type>text</type>
          <name>1-2-5-data-inventory-schedule-milestones-title</name>
          <label>Title</label>
          <options/>
          <value>
            <value>Publication of updated PDL</value>
          </value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>textarea</type>
          <name>1-2-5-data-inventory-schedule-milestones-description</name>
          <label>Description</label>
          <options/>
          <value>
            <value>This major effort consists of mapping currently known datasets to the Project Open Data Schema and ensuring publication into PDL JSON format for harvesting into data.gov.  &#xD;
</value>
          </value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>text</type>
          <name>1-2-5-data-inventory-schedule-milestones-date</name>
          <label>Milestone Date</label>
          <options/>
          <value>
            <value>monthly</value>
          </value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>textarea</type>
          <name>1-2-5-data-inventory-schedule-milestones-expand-description</name>
          <label>Description of how this milestone expands the Inventory</label>
          <options/>
          <value>
            <value>NASA is using the Project Open Data metadata schema to build the Public Data Lists and the Enterprise Data Inventory., We are continually adding datasets owned by NASA's Mission Directorates and other functional offices.  We are developing an agency-level NASA Information Architecture Management (NIAM) process to help us share and reuse the data across the agency, and allow our researchers to more easily identify common research datasets across agencies. The information architecture is one of our Open Government Plan flagship initiatives. We are making significant progress with common metadata, contract language, and search capacity. As we mature this process, identification of datasets will be more streamlined so that we can add new agency data to our inventory     </value>
          </value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>textarea</type>
          <name>1-2-5-data-inventory-schedule-milestones-enrich-description</name>
          <label>Description of how this milestone enriches the Inventory</label>
          <options/>
          <value>
            <value>The data from each Mission Directorate is unique; therefore, expanding the inventory greatly. NASA currently has over 3000 datasets within the data.gov catalog and will continue to expand this through collaboration with the Mission Directorates and through our customer engagement methods such as challenges and prizes competitions.    &#xD;
NASA has enriched the data by applying categories as seen on http://data.nasa.gov/.   The categories include Aeronautics, Earth Science, Climate, Engineering, Institutional, Life Science, Operations, and Space Science.   These categories were identified by the NASA Open Innovation Team based on NASA mission data most frequently accessed via the program websites or customer-facing programs.   </value>
          </value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>textarea</type>
          <name>1-2-5-data-inventory-schedule-milestones-open-description</name>
          <label>Description of how this milestone opens the Inventory</label>
          <options/>
          <value>
            <value>Each monthly milestone adds new datasets to open the inventory.  The NASA Open Innovation Team collaborates with the data owners to make the datasets available in machine-readable format for ease of use by our customers and the public. As an engineering and science agency, NASA has protocols to ensure sensitive data, such as ITAR-related or privacy data is secured. NASA has always and will continue to proactively release our non-sensitive scientific data for the benefit of the general public. This not only increases the level of transparency and accountability, but also improves the timely sharing of the data for better science and technology. One of the examples of NASA&#x2019;s commitment to proactively disclose information is our Scientific and Technical Information (STI) Program. The STI program is a critical component in the worldwide activity of scientific and technical aerospace research and development. This program houses over 4 million documents. Yes, we have our work cut out to convert these documents into machine-readable format &#x2013; with no additional funded authorized by Congress to make this happen.&#xD;
NASA places a high priority on protecting all our sensitive unclassified information (SBU) created, collected, maintained, and managed on behalf of NASA. Among the various categories of SBU, privacy information (identifiable form, personally identifiable information, and information subject to the Privacy Act of 1974, are among the most sensitive, requiring multiple levels of protection and compliance with federal standards and laws. Meeting these requirements ensures that NASA complies with all related federal laws and standards, and ensures NASA and the federal government retain the public trust. All system, application, and information owners must fully comply with NASA Privacy Policy and Procedures, and all employees are required to maintain a state of awareness and training that ensures we are able to appropriately protect such information. NASA&#x2019;s Privacy Page provides greater detail&#xD;
The Open Innovation team defers to the strictly-defined processes within each mission program and organization to ensure the data can be made available to the public. Once NASA data is deemed open by the technical experts through their processes and the agency privacy review process, the Open Innovation team converts it to machine-readable format for inclusion in the data inventory.</value>
          </value>
        </field>
      </fields>
      <multiple>1</multiple>
    </item>
    <item id="1.2.6">
      <parent>1.2</parent>
      <text>Develop Customer Feedback Process</text>
      <due>17 months</due>
      <due_date>2013/10/23</due_date>
      <fields>
        <field>
          <type>textarea</type>
          <name>1-2-6-customer-feedback-process</name>
          <label>Describe the agency's process to engage with customers</label>
          <options/>
          <value>NASA engages with the public through a variety of avenues, perhaps the most relevant to the Digital Strategy initiative and Open Data Policy being our commitment to open data and open source software. Two platforms, data.nasa.gov and code.nasa.gov, serve as the home for the agency's customer engagement efforts.&#xD;
&#xD;
Code.nasa.gov expands NASA&#x2019;s open source activities, surfaces existing activities, and guides internal and external groups in open development, release, and contribution. In doing so, NASA hopes to lower barriers to building open technology in partnership with the public. Future plans for code.nasa.gov include closer integration with our GitHub presence as well as improved catalogs of our available APIs and software release processes.   If you are a developer employed by NASA or a NASA contractor and have open source code you wish to host on the NASA GitHub repository, email NASA at opensource@lists.nasa.gov.&#xD;
&#xD;
Data.nasa.gov is NASA&#x2019;s flagship platform for sharing information about the vast data we collect and store - over 100 years of U.S. aeronautics and space data. Developers, technologists, entrepreneurs, citizen scientists and many others can contribute directly to the exploration of space and Earth by helping to create new ways of looking at this data. As part of the Open Government Initiative, the Agency is working to improve accessibility to this data and incentivizing the use of government data by citizens. To address the ever-increasing amount of tools and data catalogs that are publicly available on NASA&#x2019;s many websites, this directory lists publicly available datasets and serves to streamline the process for posting these datasets on data.gov. The directory includes information and direct links to more than 3000 datasets.&#xD;
</value>
        </field>
      </fields>
      <multiple/>
    </item>
    <item id="1.2.7">
      <parent>1.2</parent>
      <text>Develop Data Publication Process</text>
      <due>17 months</due>
      <due_date>2013/10/23</due_date>
      <fields>
        <field>
          <type>textarea</type>
          <name>1-2-7-data-publication-process</name>
          <label>Describe the agency's data publication process</label>
          <options/>
          <value>NASA has made its scientific, research and program data available to the public for decades.  Transparency and openness were written into our DNA more than 50 years ago with the original Space Act that established the agency in 1958.  The NASA Open Innovation Team continues to collaborate with the agency Mission Directorates to identify, collect, and format existing terabytes of data that are routinely made available through open sources, most often mission program websites. All NASA public-facing websites must be reviewed and approved through the privacy process to ensure that it meets with established data security requirements. Data available on the mission websites is converted to machine-readable format using the Open Data standards, published on data.NASA.gov, and harvested by the data.gov process for publication on the metadata catalogs on data.gov.&#xD;
&#xD;
NASA hosts data across several programs and projects and provides a meta-data publication hub on data.nasa.gov.  Using data.nasa.gov to allow CRUD operations on identified data sets for our agency public data list, will allow NASA to push data to data.gov for publication.&#xD;
</value>
        </field>
      </fields>
      <multiple/>
    </item>
    <item id="2.2">
      <parent/>
      <text>Make high-value data and content in at least two existing, major customer-facing systems available through web APIs, apply metadata tagging and publish a plan to transition additional high-value systems</text>
      <due>12 months</due>
      <due_date>2013/05/23</due_date>
      <fields>
        <field>
          <type>select</type>
          <name>2-2-status</name>
          <label>Overall Status</label>
          <options>
            <option>
              <label>Not Started</label>
              <value>not-started</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>In Progress</label>
              <value>in-progress</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>Completed</label>
              <value>completed</value>
            </option>
          </options>
          <value>completed</value>
        </field>
      </fields>
      <multiple/>
    </item>
    <item id="2.2.1">
      <parent>2.1</parent>
      <text>Publish plan on future activity</text>
      <due>12 months</due>
      <due_date>2013/05/23</due_date>
      <fields>
        <field>
          <type>textarea</type>
          <name>2-2-1-describe</name>
          <label>Describe policy</label>
          <options/>
          <value>NASA is committed to making our data, software, and tools available to the public to spur innovation and improve lives of citizens of this planet. We are looking for ways to create create machine-readable files for every NASA website &#x2013; as we do with 508 compliance processes. This is a longer-term solution to the commitment to make our data accessible. In the short-term, we will continue to convert data-sets as they come available and we have the resources to make this a reality. We will continue to engage one-on-one with data-consuming citizens through challenges and collaboration opportunities to enable citizen developers around the world to help us in our quest to further the transparency and accessibility of NASA data systems. Events like the International Space Apps Challenge open the opportunity for thousands of citizen developers from across the planet to contribute their time to use NASA data to solve problems facing their communities at the local level&#xD;
NASA has hosted three International Space Apps Challenge events. In the 2013 event, 83 cities around the world with over 9,100 participants created 770 unique, open source solutions to a series of challenges the agency issued. In 2014, over 8000 participates in 95 cities and 46 countries engaged with NASA&#x2019;s data to create 671 solutions. The challenges varied in scope and subject, from the creation of visualizations of our data to creating new API interfaces to legacy datasets. Solvers created innovative methods to monitor air, water, and urban pollution, track environmental mishaps, and alerts to warn citizens of weather and health-related disasters, as well as track the asteroids and celestial events. NASA is building on these efforts, and collaborating with other agencies to create solver profiles that can be used by citizens to engage with NASA and other agencies on a long-term basis. We're also developing innovation pipelines to help accelerate the infusion of data solutions at the local host level, as well as to infuse the solutions back into mainstream NASA.&#xD;
</value>
        </field>
      </fields>
      <multiple/>
    </item>
    <item id="2.2.2">
      <parent>2.1</parent>
      <text>Make 2+ systems (datasets) available via web APIs with metadata tags</text>
      <due>12 months</due>
      <due_date>2013/05/23</due_date>
      <fields>
        <field>
          <type>text</type>
          <name>2-2-2-system</name>
          <label>Name of system</label>
          <options/>
          <value>
            <value>NASA Data API</value>
            <value>Earth Observing System (EOS) Clearing House (ECHO)</value>
          </value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>textarea</type>
          <name>2-2-2-description</name>
          <label>Description of system</label>
          <options/>
          <value>
            <value>The data.nasa.gov API allows a machine-readable interface to return metadata from the site organized by category, tag, date, or search term. We&#x2019;re hoping this allows new and creative visualizations of the data resources NASA provides to the public. Additionally, it is a learning experience for us as we work to expand transparency, participation, and collaboration at NASA through new uses of technology.</value>
            <value>The NASA-developed Earth Observing System (EOS) Clearinghouse (ECHO) is a spatial and temporal metadata registry and order broker built by NASA's Earth Science Data and Information System (ESDIS) that enables the science community to more easily use and exchange NASA's data and services. ECHO's main objective is to enable broader use of NASA's EOS data. It allows users to more efficiently search and access data and services and increases the potential for interoperability with new tools and services. The value of these resources increases as the potential to exchange and interoperate increases. ECHO has been working with other organizations to provide their Earth science metadata alongside NASA's for users to search and access. ECHO stores metadata from a variety of science disciplines and domains, including Climate Variability and Change, Carbon Cycle and Ecosystems, Earth Surface and Interior, Atmospheric Composition, Weather, and Water and Energy Cycle.</value>
          </value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>select</type>
          <name>2-2-2-scope</name>
          <label>Scope of system</label>
          <options>
            <option>
              <label>Internal</label>
              <value>internal</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>External</label>
              <value>external</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>Both</label>
              <value>both</value>
            </option>
          </options>
          <value>
            <value>both</value>
            <value>both</value>
          </value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>text</type>
          <name>2-2-2-customers</name>
          <label>Main Customers</label>
          <options/>
          <value>
            <value>Employees, Public</value>
            <value>Employees, Public</value>
          </value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>text</type>
          <name>2-2-2-uii</name>
          <label>Unique Investment Identifier</label>
          <options/>
          <value>
            <value> 026-000000001</value>
            <value>026-000000001</value>
          </value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>text</type>
          <name>2-2-2-url</name>
          <label>API Link</label>
          <options/>
          <value>
            <value>http://data.nasa.gov/api-info/</value>
            <value>http://api.echo.nasa.gov/echo/</value>
          </value>
        </field>
      </fields>
      <multiple>1</multiple>
    </item>
    <item id="5.3">
      <parent/>
      <text>Evaluate the government-wide contract vehicles in the alternatives analysis for all new mobile-related procurements</text>
      <due>12 months</due>
      <due_date>2013/05/23</due_date>
      <fields>
        <field>
          <type>select</type>
          <name>5-3-status</name>
          <label>Overall Status</label>
          <options>
            <option>
              <label>Not Started</label>
              <value>not-started</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>In Progress</label>
              <value>in-progress</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>Completed</label>
              <value>completed</value>
            </option>
          </options>
          <value>completed</value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>textarea</type>
          <name>5-3-policy</name>
          <label>Describe Implementation</label>
          <options/>
          <value>As part of NASA's transition to ACES, the consolidated solution for delivering end-user services across the agency to achieve increased efficiencies and reduced costs through standardization, the agency undertook an extensive review of mobile device and service procurements. The agency offers employees a variety of device and service options, and is currently researching other opportunities for further flexibility in mobile services, including bring your own device programs and enhanced teleworking options.</value>
        </field>
      </fields>
      <multiple/>
    </item>
    <item id="6.3">
      <parent/>
      <text>Ensure all new digital services follow digital services and customer experience improvement guidelines</text>
      <due>12 months</due>
      <due_date>2013/05/23</due_date>
      <fields>
        <field>
          <type>select</type>
          <name>6-3-status</name>
          <label>Overall Status</label>
          <options>
            <option>
              <label>Not Started</label>
              <value>not-started</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>In Progress</label>
              <value>in-progress</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>Completed</label>
              <value>completed</value>
            </option>
          </options>
          <value>completed</value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>textarea</type>
          <name>6-3-policy</name>
          <label>Describe Implementation</label>
          <options/>
          <value>As part of NASA's Digital Governance, the agency is working to established improved digital service guidelines, many of which will be realized within the NASA&#x2019;s Web Services Initiative, which is transitioning our web presence in to a modern, cloud-based, open source environment.</value>
        </field>
      </fields>
      <multiple/>
    </item>
    <item id="7.2">
      <parent/>
      <text>Optimize at least two existing priority customer-facing services for mobile use and publish a plan for improving additional existing services</text>
      <due>12 months</due>
      <due_date>2013/05/23</due_date>
      <fields>
        <field>
          <type>select</type>
          <name>7-2-status</name>
          <label>Overall Status</label>
          <options>
            <option>
              <label>Not Started</label>
              <value>not-started</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>In Progress</label>
              <value>in-progress</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>Completed</label>
              <value>completed</value>
            </option>
          </options>
          <value>completed</value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>textarea</type>
          <name>7-2-policy</name>
          <label>Describe Implementation</label>
          <options/>
          <value>As mobile devices continue to count for a larger percentage of overall web traffic in the US, NASA has strived to offer a variety of services in mobile friendly offerings, including via specialized mobile applications, mobile optimized websites, and SMS gateways. With constrained budgetary resources, however, relying solely on NASA programs to release mobile interfaces is not the best approach to furthering this objective. Thus, our strategy has been to launch a series of challenges and collaboration opportunities to enable citizen developers around the world to help us in our quest to further the reach of NASA in to the mobile landscape. Events like the International Space Apps Challenge open the opportunity for thousands of citizen developers from across the planet to contribute their time to helping the agency create mobile interfaces for our programs.</value>
        </field>
      </fields>
      <multiple/>
    </item>
    <item id="7.2.1">
      <parent>7.2.</parent>
      <text>Report on services</text>
      <due>12 months</due>
      <due_date>2013/05/23</due_date>
      <fields>
        <field>
          <type>text</type>
          <name>7-2-1-name</name>
          <label>Service Name</label>
          <options/>
          <value>
            <value>WebTADS Mobile</value>
            <value>NASA Contacts</value>
          </value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>textarea</type>
          <name>7-2-1-description</name>
          <label>Service Description</label>
          <options/>
          <value>
            <value>WebTADS Mobile is a lighter version of the desktop-based WebTADS developed to provide NASA Civil Servants with the convenience of recording time when they're not in the office or connected via VPN.</value>
            <value> Look up your NASA colleagues' contact information directly from your phone.</value>
          </value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>select</type>
          <name>7-2-1-scope</name>
          <label>System Scope</label>
          <options>
            <option>
              <label>Internal</label>
              <value>internal</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>External</label>
              <value>external</value>
            </option>
            <option>
              <label>Both</label>
              <value>both</value>
            </option>
          </options>
          <value>
            <value>internal</value>
            <value>internal</value>
          </value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>text</type>
          <name>7-2-1-customers</name>
          <label>Primary customers</label>
          <options/>
          <value>
            <value>Employees</value>
            <value>Employees</value>
          </value>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>text</type>
          <name>7-2-1-uii</name>
          <label>Unique Investment Identifier</label>
          <options/>
          <value/>
        </field>
        <field>
          <type>text</type>
          <name>7-2-1-url</name>
          <label>URL of service</label>
          <options/>
          <value>
            <value>https://apps.nasa.gov/content/webtads</value>
            <value>https://apps.nasa.gov/content/nasa-contacts</value>
          </value>
        </field>
      </fields>
      <multiple>1</multiple>
    </item>
  </items>
</report>
